Are ya ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Aye-aye, Captain!
是的，队长！
I can't hear you!
我听不到你说话！
Aye-aye, Captain!
是的，队长！
♪ Oh ♪
♪哦♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants! ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！ ♪
♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
♪ 吸水性、黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants! ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！ ♪
♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
♪ 如果是航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants! ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！ ♪
♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
♪ 然后掉到甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
- ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants! ♪
- Ready?
- ♪ 海绵宝宝！ ♪
- 准备好了吗？
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants! ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！ ♪
Argh!
啊！
Steady, Plankton.
稳住，浮游生物。
Careful.
小心。
Ooh!
哦！
What is all that noise?
这些噪音是什么？
What is so funny?
有什么好笑的？
- This!
- Huh?
- 这！
- 啊？
Hopping hineys!
跳跃海尼！
Put those away!
把那些收起来！
Oh, don't be embarrassed.
哦，别尴尬。
It's just your baby pictures.
这只是你宝宝的照片。
You were adorable.
你很可爱。
I was never adorable.
我从来就不可爱。
These photos have got to go.
这些照片必须删除。
Whoa!
哇！
You were such a cute baby.
你真是个可爱的宝宝。
Oh, I can't stand it!
唉，我受不了了！
Yoink!
哟哟！
- Aw.
- Boo!
- 噢。
- 嘘！
I'm not cute
and adorable.
我不可爱
和可爱的。
I'm horrifying and evil!
我是可怕又邪恶的！
Hmph!
哼！
Plankton was the cutest baby
I've ever seen
浮游生物是最可爱的宝宝
我曾经见过
and I'm gonna prove it to him.
我会向他证明这一点。
Eh, keeps him off the streets.
嗯，让他远离街头。
Time to eat, Moby.
吃饭时间到了，莫比。
Oh, you're gonna love
this new whale baby food.
哦，你一定会喜欢的
这种新的鲸鱼婴儿食品。
It's called Baleen Baby...
它的名字叫“巴林宝贝”
baby.
婴儿。
Open up!
打开！
No!
不！
Come on, Moby.
来吧，莫比。
Here comes the submarine
into the lagoon!
潜艇来了
进入泻湖！
No!
不！
Mmm!
嗯！
Da-Da!
哒哒！
I want my Baleen Baby...
我想要我的巴林宝宝...
...baby!
...婴儿！
He called me Da-Da!
他叫我达达！
Your kids will call you Da-Da
你的孩子会叫你Da-Da
as they go ga-ga
他们嘎嘎嘎嘎
for the delicious taste
of Baleen Baby...
为了美味
巴林宝贝...
baby!
宝贝！
And now it's time
to announce the winner...
现在是时候了
宣布获胜者...
...of Baleen Baby food's
cutest baby contest!
...Baleen 婴儿食品
最可爱宝宝大赛！
Baby Plankton!
浮游生物宝宝！
Woo-hoo!
呜呼！
Yay! Plankton, look!
耶！浮游生物，看！
SpongeBob was right!
海绵宝宝是对的！
I don't have time
for malarkey now, Karen.
我没有时间
现在就胡言乱语吧，凯伦。
I just ran out of robot oil.
我的机器人油刚刚用完。
Look for Baby Plankton's
picture
寻找浮游生物宝宝
图片
on every jar
of Baleen Baby baby food.
在每个罐子上
Baleen Baby 婴儿食品。
Baby!
宝贝！
Oh, he's gonna love that.
哦，他会喜欢的。
There he is. It's him!
他就在那里。是他！
I can't believe it.
我简直不敢相信。
Oh, man!
哦，伙计！
Oh, pardon me.
哦，请原谅我。
After you.
您先请。
Hm. People usually step on me
when I'm shopping.
嗯。人们经常踩我
当我购物时。
Strange.
奇怪的。
Ah, robot oil.
啊，机器人油。
Time to get climbing.
是时候去爬山了。
Oh. Oh, no.
哦。哦，不。
Let me get that for you.
让我帮你拿一下。
Um, thanks?
嗯，谢谢？
Anytime, cutie.
任何时候，小可爱。
I am not a cutie!
我不是小可爱！
Okay, what do I owe you?
好吧，我欠你什么？
It's on the house, sir!
先生，就在房子里！
On account of you being so...
正因为你如此...
...famous!
...著名的！
It's pronounced "infamous,"
but okay...
发音是“臭名昭著”
但好吧...
Have a nice day!
祝你今天过得愉快！
I seen that butt on the TV!
我在电视上看到过那个屁股！
I want my Baleen Baby...
我想要我的 Baleen 宝贝...
baby!
宝贝！
What was that?
那是什么？
Blimping butt cracks!
屁股裂开了！
Buy some Baleen Baby!
买一些鲸鱼宝宝！
Huh?
啊？
Karen!
凯伦！
How dare you give out
my baby mugshots
你怎么敢给出
我的宝贝照片
without my permission!
未经我允许！
As much as I'd like to, Sheldon,
只要我愿意，谢尔顿，
I can't take credit
for this one.
我不能相信
对于这个。
I did it!
我做到了！
Now aren't you happier knowing
现在你知道了不是更高兴吗
that you're still
the cutest baby in town?
你还在
镇上最可爱的宝宝？
No!
不！
I want to strike fear
in the hearts of everyone,
我想要打击恐惧
在每个人的心中，
not make old ladies
pinch my cheek.
不让老太太
捏我的脸颊。
Look at these pinch marks.
看看这些捏痕。
That looks painful.
Sorry about that, Plankton.
看起来很痛苦。
抱歉，浮游生物。
Sorry is for suckers,
SpongeBoob.
对不起是给傻瓜的，
海绵宝宝。
You got me
into this baby picture mess
你得到了我
进入这张混乱的婴儿照片
and you're gonna help me
clean it up!
你会帮助我的
把它清理干净！
I'm ready!
我准备好了！
Here's the plan.
这是计划。
We cover up
all my baby pictures.
我们掩盖
我所有的婴儿照片。
Got it!
知道了！
But first,
但首先，
we chop down the billboards.
我们砍掉广告牌。
Whoa!
哇！
Then, we paint over
the bus ads.
然后，我们画一遍
公交车广告。
Fire!
火！
Whoa!
哇！
I'm okay!
我没事！
And finally,
最后，
we buy up the entire supply
我们买下了全部供应
of Baleen Baby food...
Baleen 婴儿食品...
...and bury it in the desert!
...并将其埋在沙漠中！
- Phew.
- Oh, boy.
- 唷。
- 哦，男孩。
We did it!
我们做到了！
Nobody will ever see
my naked baby photos again.
没有人会看到
又是我的裸体婴儿照片。
Wh-wh-what the heck was that?
什、什、那到底是什么？
S-s-sea coyotes?
S-S-海土狼？
Aw, it's just a bunch
of whale babies.
噢，这只是一堆
鲸鱼宝宝。
They're adorable.
他们很可爱。
Why are they staring at me
like that?
他们为什么盯着我
就这样？
They probably smell
the baby food.
他们可能闻到
婴儿食品。
What do baby whales eat anyway?
小鲸鱼吃什么？
Who cares?
谁在乎？
Toss 'em a jar
and make 'em go away.
扔给他们一个罐子
并让他们走开。
Break it up, babies.
Break it up.
分手吧，宝贝们。
打破它。
"Baleen Baby food
is made of 100%..."
“巴林婴儿食品
是由 100% 制成的……”
"Gulp"?
“咕噜”？
What the heck is "gulp"?
“吞”到底是什么？
"100%...
“100%...
p-p-p-plankton"?
浮游生物”？
Baleen Baby is plankton!
鲸须宝宝是浮游生物！
Run!
跑步！
Ooh!
哦！
Where are they all coming from?
他们都是从哪里来的？
I don't know.
我不知道。
But I really dig
their whale song.
但我真的很挖
他们的鲸鱼之歌。
Don't listen, SpongeBob!
别听，海绵宝宝！
Some say
the song of a baby whale
有人说
小鲸鱼的歌声
is so hypnotic...
太催眠了...
...it can turn you
into a voracious,
...它可以让你转变
变成贪婪的、
plankton-eating...
吃浮游生物的...
whale!
鲸！
I want my mama!
我想要我的妈妈！
Sweet Neptune!
甜蜜的海王星！
Ew, chum!
呃，伙计！
I must have lost a bet.
我一定是打赌输了。
Help!
帮助！
That's a relief.
这真是一种解脱。
I thought you guys
were gonna eat--
我以为你们
我们要吃——
Yuck!
哎呀！
Ew!
呃！
All right, babies,
leave Plankton alone now.
好吧，宝贝们，
现在别管浮游生物了。
Look what they did
to my antennas, Mommy.
看看他们做了什么
到我的天线，妈妈。
- Whoa!
- I'd know that hiney anywhere.
- 哇！
- 我在任何地方都会认识那个海尼。
Those are Baby Plankton's
famous buns.
这些是浮游生物宝宝的
有名的包子。
I'll kick your buns, you weirdo!
我会踢你的面包，你这个怪人！
I'm just here to give you
the Baleen Baby contest check
我只是来给你
Baleen Baby 竞赛支票
for one jillion dollars...
为了一十亿美元...
baby!
婴儿！
Well...
出色地...
that's a baby food
of a different flavor.
那是婴儿食品
的不同风味。
I accept!
我接受！
Huh? What's that?
啊？那是什么？
Baby Plankton tastes like chum?
浮游生物宝宝尝起来像密友吗？
Ew. That's not gonna be good
for business.
呃。那不会有什么好事
为了生意。
Okay, change of plans!
好吧，计划改变！
We're done
with Dr. Cyclops here,
我们完成了
和独眼巨人博士在这里，
so let's go with the second
best baby photo we have.
那么我们来看看第二个
我们有最好的婴儿照片。
What the...
什么...
Krabs?
螃蟹？
Oh yeah. I forgot.
哦，是的。我忘了。
I sent in Mr. Krabs'
baby photo, too.
我派了蟹老板的
婴儿照片也可以。
Actually, that's adorable.
事实上，这很可爱。
My pinchable cheeks!
我那可捏的脸颊！